[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Each question below consists of a related pair of words; select the pair that best expresses a relationship similar to that expressed in the original pair. SUBMISSION : YIELDING",
    "options": [
      "Subjection : Liberation",
      "Restrain : Indulge",
      "Restriction : Relaxation",
      "Complaint : Acquiescent"
    ],
    "answer": "Complaint : Acquiescent"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Vacillate : Hesitate",
    "options": [
      "Persevere : Waiver",
      "Impulsive : Deliberate",
      "Irresolute : Indecisive",
      "Obstinate : Accommodating"
    ],
    "answer": "Irresolute : Indecisive"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Assert : Dissent",
    "options": [
      "Endorse : Ratify",
      "Reject : Disapprove",
      "Affirm : Object",
      "Acknowledge : Recognize"
    ],
    "answer": "Affirm : Object"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Distort : Twist",
    "options": [
      "Deform : Reform",
      "Harmonize : Balance",
      "Observe : Blur",
      "Straighten : Bend"
    ],
    "answer": "Harmonize : Balance"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "‘Government has been entrusted ___ Elected politicians’",
    "options": ["at", "with", "for", "to"],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "He has paid the penalty __ his crimes __ five years in prision.",
    "options": ["at- by", "for- with", "about- at", "after- in"],
    "answer": "for- with"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The path __ paved, so we were able to walk through the path.",
    "options": ["being", "was", "had been", "has been"],
    "answer": "was"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "In spite of my requests, he did not ___",
    "options": ["get off", "in", "give in", "give forth"],
    "answer": "give in"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The children studied in a class room ___ windows were never opened.",
    "options": ["whose", "where", "which", "that"],
    "answer": "whose"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Fill in the gaps by choosing one word from the choices given. 'To stay healthy, we must plan to have a balanced___'.",
    "options": ["figure", "outlook", "diet", "food"],
    "answer": "diet"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "We must keep our fingers ___ that the weather will stay fine for the picnic tomorrow.",
    "options": ["lifted", "raised", "pointed", "crossed"],
    "answer": "crossed"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "They have ___ their support for our case.",
    "options": ["provided", "disavowed", "pledged", "deferred"],
    "answer": "pledged"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Choose the correct meaning of the following words : Cul-de-sac",
    "options": ["bubble", "error", "selection", "dead end"],
    "answer": "dead end"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "'Parcel' indicates---",
    "options": ["Quarrel", "Unobstructed view", "Piece of land", "Postage"],
    "answer": "Piece of land"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "'Ruminant' indicates--",
    "options": ["Soup", "Cud-chewing animal", "Noise-maker", "Gossip"],
    "answer": "Cud-chewing animal"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Find out the correct answer.",
    "options": [
      "Telescopes and data bases have nothing in common for the astronomer",
      "Telescopes and data bases are both becoming relevant for the astronomer",
      "Telescopes and data bases complement each other for the astronomer",
      "Telescopes and Data bases can be confusing to the astronomer"
    ],
    "answer": "Telescopes and data bases complement each other for the astronomer"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "\"\"\"Data bases sit on computer disks, humming away\" implies\"",
    "options": [
      "Data baes are unless and static",
      "\"\"\"Data bases sit on computer disks, humming away\" implies\"",
      "Data baes are things of the past",
      "Data baes are singing instrument"
    ],
    "answer": "\"\"\"Data bases sit on computer disks, humming away\" implies\""
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "\"Modern data base 'Produce reams of observational data\"",
    "options": [
      "Data basses are of limited use in storing information",
      "Data bases create information instantly",
      "Data bases produce lot of information",
      "Data bases are packed with paper"
    ],
    "answer": "Data bases produce lot of information"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "The contemporary astronomer needs to look at the sky from a mountain top",
    "options": [
      "contemporary astronomer needs a telescope equipped with digital sensors to explore the universe",
      "contemporary astronomer needs a telescope equipped with digital sensors to explore the universe",
      "The contemporary astronomer needs a telescope to explore the universe",
      "None of those"
    ],
    "answer": "contemporary astronomer needs a telescope equipped with digital sensors to explore the universe"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "A good title for the passage will be —",
    "options": [
      "Telescope and exploration of the universe",
      "Space exploration in the new millennium",
      "Astronomers and exploration of the universe",
      "Digital telescope and exploration of the universe"
    ],
    "answer": "Digital telescope and exploration of the universe"
  }
]
